Jie Ma (Jay)

codejma@gmail.com
0433 808 445

http://jma.dev
https://github.com/imjma
https://www.linkedin.com/in/jiema/

SUMMARY

ABC: Always be coding

I am a senior software engineer with PHP/Golang experience mainly, and one-year full stack experience. Also I am an edge technology lover.

I am a fast and keen learner with a good attention to details and excellent troubleshooting skills. I am also a good team player who has a proven ability to work analytically. I am highly efficient, deadline focused, and handle multiple projects at same time.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer @ Australian Broadcasting Corporation - Jun 2018 - Present

Terminus is an API that aggregates and normalises data from multiple internal ABC sources to provide a unified view of ABC data in an organisable, customisable, layout order data set.

Terminus API has been used by ABC news, triplej app, iview, ABC website, ABC apple news, and other ABC services.

Also guarantee a high level of scalability, even if internal APIs are not able to handle that much load and currently get about 10 million unique API hits a day.

Architecture: Golang, GraphQL, Redis, AWS Lambda, Docker

Senior Software Engineer @ Switch Media - Sep 2017 - Jun 2018

AdEase enables world-class multi-screen server-side ad insertion for both Live and VOD content with zero buffering and a continuous TV-like experience.

- AdEase API Cloud Solution (PHP 7) Refactor legacy system into new RESTful API
- Storage Service (Golang) Upload data to cloud (GCS/AWS)
- Encoder Queue (Lumen) RESTful API and jobs queue system that send requests to encoding system
- Ad Buffer (Golang) Retriever Ads from other system, keep in the Redis, and ready to be requested

- ID3 Tag injection (Golang) Refactor legacy PHP script that insert ID3 tags into segment
- Stream Monitor (Golang) Parsing Manifest/Playlist into JSON that been used in AdEase API

Architecture: PHP7, Golang, Docker, Redis, GCS, AWS EC2, AWS S3

Software Engineer @ Salmat - Jan 2017 - Sep 2017

Work with some of Australia and New Zealand's largest and most trusted brands, helping them get closer to their customers. Also provide multi-site businesses with one simple platform that controls execution of marketing collateral across different channels.

- Building new internal system that use Laravel and ReactJS
- Maintain and continuously feature develop the system with Zend 1 framework
- Understand business requirements and design solutions
- Development of high traffic and large scale web application
- Code review, documentation, testing, bug-fixes, technical support

Architecture: Laravel 5.4, Zend 1, ReactJS/Redux, MySQL, AWS EC2, AWS S3

Web Developer @ Devhub July 2016 - Jan 2017

- Build a new partial React.js website based on existing website (projectmate.com.au)
- Solely responsible for full stack development of multiply React.js/Rails apps (mealmonster.com.au, little-lion.net)

Architecture: React.js, Redux, Bootstrap, Rails, Sidekiq, Sendgrid, Stripe

Agentbox CRM System is a leading CRM system to the Australian real estate industry. The system is built by PHP with procedure code. We moved to use Symfony 2 framework from the end of 2015 that make the code more reusable, readable and efficiency.

- Responsible for maintaining legacy business logical code
- Responsible for refactoring legacy business logical code into Symfony framework
- Responsible for developing new features/business logic with Symfony framework

Architecture: Symfony 2, MySOL, LAMP, Composer, Mootools, jOuery, AWS S3

Agentbox Go System

Agentbox GO System is a mobile and simplifies version of Agentbox CRM System. The system is built by PHP with object-oriented programming.

• Responsible for developing the system to migrate latest features from CRM system

Architecture: PHP, MySQL, LAMP, jQuery Mobile

Version Coordinator

- Responsible for reviewing the code of pull request
- Responsible for releasing new version to clients
- Responsible for maintaining and developing internal client management system

Other Ongoing Projects

Email Distributed System

When client requests sending emails, it will slice it into parts and distribute each part to different email servers by random, and call to send emails through centralized server on order.

Realestate Portals Export System

Exporting client's properties information with XML format, to portals, such as realestate.com.au, domain.com.au, and others.

Email Log Analysis System

It analyses email logs which receive from portals such as realestate.com.au and domain.com.au, and add results to the database, client requests to fetch data, and it will return JSON result to them.

Other scripts for ritual repeatable jobs

Write small scripts to replace human repeatable jobs, like to generate monthly reports

EDUCATION

University of Wollongong — Master of Computer Science, 2007 - 2008 University of Wollongong — Bachelor of Computer Science, 2005 - 2007

SKILLS

Expert in PHP with Symfony 2, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Advanced in Rails, SQL, React.js, jQuery, Mootools, Git, RESTful, SASS

Experienced in AWS, ES6, Babel, Bootstrap, XML, Unit Testing, Backbone

INTERESTS

- Photography: my Instagram [@ishotsth](https://www.instagram.com/ishotsth/)
- Traveling: view the world, and take photos
- Mobile/Desktop Applications: like to try new apps on both mobile or desktop
- Gadget: always like new gadgets
- Learning edge tech: keep learning and updating myself.
- Watching: like comedy and sci-fi